Senior Full Stack Web Developer

SUMMARY

Hello, my name is Brian. I'm an experienced full stack web engineer, I started out back in 2000 as a LAMP developer until 2011, when I pivoted to .Net. I have a lot of database and stored procedure experience on multiple databases. I recently took time out to get training for the last three years in rust and cyber security and have an cyber security professional certificate from ISC2. Now I am ready to help you make your next project a total success!

EXPERIENCE

Massive Resources, Inc, Contract Wordpress Developer March 2022 - Current

- Developed in house plugins for marketing and social media.
- Manage their current servers for security and regular backup.
- Build custom themes for customers with css3, javascript and html5.

VerifyToday
Contract .Net/Python/Django Engineer
Jun 2021 - Feb 2022 (9 months)

- Migrated their legacy paid search product, written in visual basic script, and rewrote it in modern .Net MSMVC/C# with Typescript for reactive front end elements.
- Built a new custom ETL system with C# and Azure Storage that could also import data from SFTP and REST.
- Moved them from a single outdated license MS SQL Server and set up new TSQL logic for the enhanced search functionality in the modern version of managed SQL on Azure.
- Developed a new CI/CD system for them using Azure App Service.

• Setup a new workflow for their staff developers based on Agile and Jira.

.Net Engineer

Jul 2017 - May 2019 (1 year 11 months)

- Modernized their live video proctoring product from flash and flash media server to a new system with webrtc and .Net, deployed on Azure.
- Moved their database from Mysql to a managed Ms Sql Server on Azure.
- Deployed Janus Webrtc Service to Azure, with an MS MVC service to connect sessions from the client with websockets.
- Improved performance to allow 20 times the scale they had before.

SKILLS

.Net, Typescript, Angularjs, React, Vue, SQL, TSQL Stored Procedures, ETL, SQL Server, Postgresql, Mysql, Mongodb, Redis, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Github, CI/CD, Github Actions, Azure, AWS, Kubernetes, C++, Rust, Python, Pytorch, Machine Learning, Webrtc, Live Streaming, Jira, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Ecommerce, Payment Gateway Integration, Linq, C#, F#, Jquery, Javascript

EDUCATION

California Institute of the Arts Master of Fine Arts, Integrated Media Technology

University of California, Irvine BA, Anthropology